<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Core Functions on quobix</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/</link><description>Recent content in Core Functions on quobix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>schema</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/schema/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/schema/</guid><description>schema is a function that takes a JSON Schema definition, and validates that an object looked up via JSON Path matches that schema. If the object does not exist, the function will trigger a rule violation
How do I use this function? This function is configured by the following functionOptions
NAME DESCRIPTION TYPE REQUIRED? schema The schema you want to evaluate JSON Schema yes Example ruleset configuration openapi-tags: description: Global tags should exist, and be an array type: validation recommended: false given: &amp;#34;$&amp;#34; then: field: &amp;#34;tags&amp;#34; function: &amp;#34;schema&amp;#34; functionOptions: schema: type: &amp;#34;array&amp;#34; items: type: &amp;#34;object&amp;#34; minItems: 1 uniqueItems: true View Spectral Equivalent</description></item><item><title>alphabetical</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/alphabetical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/alphabetical/</guid><description>alphabetical will check that a given array via a JSON Path is ordered alphabetically.
The value should not be false or an empty string &amp;quot;&amp;quot; or null
How do I use this function? This function is configured by the following functionOptions. Essentially the keyedBy value is the property of the object, that is to be checked for alphabetic ordering.
NAME DESCRIPTION TYPE REQUIRED? keyedBy the key to for sorting objects string no Example ruleset configuration openapi-tags-alphabetical: description: &amp;#34;Tags should be in alphabetical order.</description></item><item><title>truthy</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/truthy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/functions/core/truthy/</guid><description>truthy will check that a given JSON Path exists, or has been defined.
The value should not be false or an empty string &amp;quot;&amp;quot; or null
Example ruleset configuration my-important-rule: description: This is an important rule message: &amp;#34;&amp;#39;chicken&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;nugget&amp;#39; is missing! Oh no! You need to add it!&amp;#34; given: $.some.path then: - field: chicken function: truthy - field: nugget function: truthy View Spectral Equivalent
View Function Source</description></item></channel></rss>