<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Operation and Path Rules on quobix</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/</link><description>Recent content in Operation and Path Rules on quobix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>path-declarations-must-exist</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-declarations-must-exist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 05:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-declarations-must-exist/</guid><description>JSON Path: $.paths When defining Paths and using Path Parameters It&amp;rsquo;s important to not add blank declarations.
This rule checks that no paths is using empty path parameters.
Why did this violation appear? One or more paths definitions has an empty parameter defined.
Bad example paths: /pizza/{}/{icecream}: get: parameters: - in: path name: &amp;#34;icecream&amp;#34; ... Good example paths: /pizza/{cake}/{icecream}: get: parameters: - in: path name: &amp;#34;cake&amp;#34; - in: path name: &amp;#34;icecream&amp;#34; .</description></item><item><title>path-keys-no-trailing-slash</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-keys-no-trailing-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 05:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-keys-no-trailing-slash/</guid><description>JSON Path: $.paths When defining Paths, it&amp;rsquo;s important to not include a trailing slash at the end of the path definition.
This rule checks that no paths definition ends with a slash &amp;lsquo;/&amp;rsquo;.
Why did this violation appear? One or more paths definitions contains a trailing slash.
Bad example paths: /pizza/{cake}/{icecream}/: get: parameters: ... Good example paths: /pizza/{cake}/{icecream}: get: parameters: ... How do I fix this violation? Ensure there are no paths definitions that end with a slash &amp;lsquo;/&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>path-not-include-query</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-not-include-query/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 05:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-not-include-query/</guid><description>JSON Path: $.paths This rule checks to ensure a paths definition does not contain a Query string.
The mistake is actually quite common with authors new to the OpenAPI standard. It happens all the time.
Why did this violation appear? One or more paths definitions contains a query string.
Bad example paths: /deserts/icecream?sprinkles=true: get: parameters: ... Good example paths: /deserts/icecream: get: parameters: - in: query name: &amp;#34;sprinkles&amp;#34; ... How do I fix this violation?</description></item><item><title>operation-operationId-valid-in-url</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid-valid-in-url/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 05:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid-valid-in-url/</guid><description>This rule is going to be re-written. Its behavior will not change, however the current implementation is not satisfactory. An Operation should always contain an operationId. This rule will check the value used is friendly to being used as part of a URL.
Documentation and code generation tools depend on this value being unique and often use it as part of URL paths.
Why did this violation appear? The operationId for one or more Operation definitions is not URL friendly.</description></item><item><title>operation-success-response</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-success-response/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:23:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-success-response/</guid><description>Check every Operation Response has either a 2xx or 3xx response code.
An operation isn&amp;rsquo;t much use, unless it returns an OK status code (2xx), or a Redirect/Choice status code (3xx)
Why did this violation appear? There is an Operation Response in your specification that isn&amp;rsquo;t returning a success response.
What is this rule checking for? Every Operation Response is checked for the following:
2xx or 3xx Response code A good example.</description></item><item><title>operation-operationId</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid/</guid><description>Every operation must have an operationId. It&amp;rsquo;s critical that all Operation&amp;rsquo;s have an identifier.
An operationId is used by documentation tools, code generators and mocking engines. It&amp;rsquo;s used to define page names, URI&amp;rsquo;s and method names in auto-generated code.
Why did this violation appear? There is an Operation in your specification that has not defined an operationId.
What is this rule checking for? Every Operation is checked for the following</description></item><item><title>operation-operationId-unique</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid-unique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-operationid-unique/</guid><description>Every operation must have an operationId that is unique. It&amp;rsquo;s critical that all Operation&amp;rsquo;s can be identified independently, without the need to analyze the path, params and verbs to locate an operation.
An operationId is used by documentation tools, code generators and mocking engines. It&amp;rsquo;s used to define page names, URI&amp;rsquo;s and method names in auto-generated code.
It needs to be unique so there are no clashes with other operations (nothing else can share that ID).</description></item><item><title>operation-parameters</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-parameters/</guid><description>Operation Parameters can be described through paths, headers cookies and queries.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to ensure that none of these parameters are duplicates, which is easier that you may think, when an operation has multiple parameter definitions across different types.
Why did this violation appear? There is a Parameter in the specification that has been duplicated or it&amp;rsquo;s using multiple input types
What is this rule checking for? Every Operation is checked for the following</description></item><item><title>operation-singular-tag</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-singular-tag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-singular-tag/</guid><description>Operation Tags are used to define operation categories or groups.
Tools use tags differently when generating code, or documentation. Sometimes, multiple tags can interfere with how tools operate.
To be honest, this rule is a bit obscure, generally it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended unless there is a specific use case for it.
Why did this violation appear? Multiple tags have been used in an operation.
What is this rule checking for? Every Operation is only allowed a single tag to be defined</description></item><item><title>operation-tag-defined</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-tag-defined/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/operation-tag-defined/</guid><description>Operation Tags are used to define operation categories or groups.
Sometimes, tags that have been defined for an operation, have not been defined as part of the global scope of the specification.
Why did this violation appear? A tag was used in an operation, without that tag being defined in the global scope.
What is this rule checking for? Every Operation has to use tags that have been declared globally as part of the tags definition.</description></item><item><title>path-params</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-params/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 15:53:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rules/operations/path-params/</guid><description>Path Parameters are pretty easy to get wrong.
Sometimes, they can be defined, but never used, or used but never defined. Sometimes they are duplicated, or set to required, but then are not defined.
There is a whole raft of issues that can appear with Path Parameters, so this rule is one of the more complex ones.
Why did this violation appear? An operation has used path parameters, but has incorrectly implemented them.</description></item></channel></rss>