<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vacuum on quobix</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/</link><description>Recent content in Vacuum on quobix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 06:24:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quobix.com/vacuum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom Functions</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/custom-functions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 08:20:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/custom-functions/</guid><description>Coming soon. Not quite ready yet. Next major feature on my list.</description></item><item><title>Core Concepts</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/concepts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 12:20:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/concepts/</guid><description>There are three core concepts when it comes to vacuum.
Function Rule RuleSet Functions power Rules and Rules make up RuleSets What are Rules? Rules are filters that define a set of target values you want to check against. Rules define what to look up, where to find it and what to check for. Those options are then sent to a function that will execute that logic.
Rules enforce a company or product API style guide.</description></item><item><title>Why should you care?</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 12:20:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/why/</guid><description>Why should I care about OpenAPI? Open API is the de-facto choice for designing and documenting REST APIs. Following an API First123 strategy allows teams to design and define, test, mock and explore APIs without building any code.
It allows service providers and consumers to work independently, using a strongly defined, rich API contract.
Why do I need an OpenAPI linter? We are human and we suck at writing. Even when something looks syntactically correct, it will probably still read like garbage.</description></item><item><title>What is vacuum?</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 06:25:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/about/</guid><description>vacuum is an ultra-super-fast, lightweight OpenAPI linter and quality checking tool, inspired by Spectral.
It&amp;rsquo;s also compatible with existing Spectral rulesets and generates compatible Spectral reports.
vacuum can suck all the lint of a 5mb OpenAPI spec in about 250ms. Designed to reliably lint OpenAPI specifications, very, very quickly. Including very large ones. Spectral. can be quite slow when used as an API and does not scale for enterprise applications.</description></item><item><title>Installing vacuum</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/installing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 06:25:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/installing/</guid><description>Install via homebrew. This the recommended approach. If you&amp;rsquo;re on MacOS or Linux, the easiest way to install vacuum is via homebrew.
brew install daveshanley/vacuum/vacuum Install via Docker. vacuum is available as a container, you can pull the image from Docker Hub.
docker pull dshanley/vacuum To run via docker, just add docker dshanley/vacuum as your command, like so:
docker dshanley/vacuum lint &amp;lt;your-openapi-spec.yaml&amp;gt; Checkout from source. git clone https://github.com/daveshanley/vacuum.git Then change directory into vacuum cd vacuum</description></item></channel></rss>