<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Understanding RuleSets on quobix</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/</link><description>Recent content in Understanding RuleSets on quobix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>All Rules</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/all/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 05:30:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/all/</guid><description>Want to throw the kitchen sink at your OpenAPI specification? Use All the rules!
To configure all the rules, you can simply use the same mechanism Spectral uses for extending a ruleset.
Create a new file (something like all-rules.yaml) and add the following YAML to it:
extends: [[spectral:oas, all]] This creates a ruleset that extends &amp;lsquo;all&amp;rsquo; rules. You can find this ruleset in the rulesets/examples directory, and it&amp;rsquo;s named all-ruleset.</description></item><item><title>Custom RuleSets</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/custom-rulesets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 05:30:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/custom-rulesets/</guid><description>Most of the time, just customizing the built-in OpenAPI Rules will get about 90% of the job done, most of the time.
At some point however, there comes a time to customize the rules and perhaps add some new ones using built-in core functions.
Don&amp;rsquo;t design APIs in a wiki. Most big companies are guaranteed to have wiki pages in Confluence (or similar), that have HTTP REST APIs that are inconsistently documented, invalid and out-of-date.</description></item><item><title>No Rules!</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/no-rules/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 05:30:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/no-rules/</guid><description>Why would anyone want no rules? what is the point of an empty RuleSet?
The main purpose of this RuleSet is to allow the individual enabling of rules
Create a new file (something like custom-rules.yaml) and add the following YAML to it:
extends: [[spectral:oas, off]] This creates a ruleset that extends &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo; rules. You can find this ruleset in the rulesets/examples directory, and it&amp;rsquo;s named norules-ruleset.yaml
Now you can enable rules individually:</description></item><item><title>Recommended Rules</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/recommended/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 05:30:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/recommended/</guid><description>Want to check against recommended rules?
Recommended rules are the default behavior from vacuum. If there is no ruleset supplied, vacuum will always run recommended rules only.
To explicitly define a &amp;lsquo;recommended only&amp;rsquo; ruleset that can be customized, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to extend a ruleset the same way that Spectral does.
Create a new file (something like recommended-rules.yaml) and add the following YAML to it:
extends: [[spectral:oas, recommended]] This creates a ruleset that extends &amp;lsquo;recommended&amp;rsquo; rules.</description></item><item><title>Understanding RuleSets</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/understanding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/rulesets/understanding/</guid><description>RuleSets are how to configure vacuum to know which rules to run for each specification, and how it should evaluate those rules.
A RuleSet is a style guide with each rule being an individual requirement as a part of the overall guide.
What does a RuleSet look like? vacuum has based RuleSet configuration on the Spectral Ruleset model. This means Spectral RuleSets are 100% compatible with vacuum1
vacuum has added an id value to the rule (which Spectral does not), this to allow backwards compatibility, and the freedom to rename and add new names to new vacuum only content.</description></item></channel></rss>