<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CLI commands on quobix</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/</link><description>Recent content in CLI commands on quobix</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 07:39:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>dashboard command</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/dashboard/</guid><description>The console UI is an early state of development, it will change. Working in a terminal is an essential and every day part of any software or DevOps engineer&amp;rsquo;s life. A terminal is perhaps the most common interface most of us use.
Console UIs are not so common these days, which is really strange.
Using a browser based app is cool, but there is something really cool about a console UI.</description></item><item><title>html-report command</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/html-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/html-report/</guid><description>working on it, check back in a few days.</description></item><item><title>report command</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/report/</guid><description>The report command will generate a high fidelity recording of a linting run. The report is a replayable data set that can be used to re-render any vacuum report using either the dashboard, or the html-report commands.
The original results are preserved and won&amp;rsquo;t be changed, regardless how many times the report is re-rendered.
vacuum report This will generate a report from your my-openapi-spec.yaml and will save the file as myreport-MM-DD-YY-HH-MM-SS.</description></item><item><title>lint command</title><link>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/lint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 07:39:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://quobix.com/vacuum/commands/lint/</guid><description>The fastest way to see something useful is to print something out to the console.
lint This will print a summary of your linting results. The lint command will use the Recommended RuleSet.
Just want to try things out? If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an OpenAPI spec and you want to see something, you can run it against one of the test specifications. A good one to try is the petstorev3.</description></item></channel></rss>